Hi, my name is Michael Orkin and I'm a television producer.
How do you become a television producer?
Well, there's a lot of different ways because becoming a television producer simply means that you are producing pieces of video that end up on television or cable.
And how do you do that?
I went to college and became a... got a degree in broadcast journalism and then went into small markets and learned how to produce television.
That's one way. Another way is to simply take your home video camera, go out, shoot things, get them edited and get them on tv, your local cable access could put it on the air for you.
And that would make you a low end television producer, but a television producer.
The best way to get into mainstream television production I think is to get a college degree in television, get in... get your foot in the door somewhere, somehow.
Get a job producing television.
That means a lot of hard work.
It means coming up with great ideas.
It means studying television, and I mean watching a lot of television, seeing what's happening 'cause television does change over time.
Right now everything is reality based.
That means coming up with a great idea for getting a crew to go out and shoot things, get them edited, get them put on tv.
It's just hard work, but that's what television... being... that's how you get to be a television producer.
It's hard work.